During the four years of living with his family day by day,
ช่วงเวลาสี่ปีที่อุทิศทุกๆ วันให้แก่ครอบครัว
Fushi grew like a human being.
ได้ทำให้ฟุชิเติบโตขึ้นมาคล้ายมนุษย์
Upon Rynn's invitation,
เพราะได้รับคำเชิญจากเพื่อนอย่างริง
Fushi and Gugu head to attend Rynn's 16th birthday party.
ฟุชิจึงได้เข้าร่วมงานวันเกิดพร้อมกับกูกู
I...
ฉัน…
However...
แต่ทว่า…
TO YOUR ETERNITY
แด่เธอผู้เป็นนิรันดร์
The "Knockers" are here.
"น็อกเกอร์" มาแล้ว
Its core is within the earth.
"แก่น" ของเจ้าสิ่งนั้นอยู่ข้างใต้นี่
They've laid their roots in the vicinity.
รากของมันแผ่ขยายครอบคลุมที่นี่
They'll destroy this area soon.
และอีกไม่นานก็คงจะทำลายที่นี่
-What's going on? -I'm scared!
-อะไรน่ะ -น่ากลัวจัง
Everyone! Outside!
ทุกคนหนีไปข้างนอกเร็ว
Take Myrr!
รับมิรุไป
You should run too!
นายก็รีบหนีเร็ว
Go! While you can...
เร็วเข้า หนีไปเดี๋ยวนี้
EPISODE 12: AWAKENING
#12 ลืมตาตื่น
Gugu!
กูกู
Someone... Someone help!
ใครก็ได้ ใครก็ได้ช่วยด้วย
What is this? It's all sticky.
นี่มันอะไรกัน ทำไมเหนียวอย่างนี้
Is it alive?
สิ่งมีชีวิตเหรอ
Grab on!
จับสิ่งนี้ไว้
Are you all right?
ไม่เป็นไรใช่ไหม
Yes. Thank you.
ขอบคุณมาก
It was just a scratch. I'm relieved.
แค่แผลเล็กน้อยน่ะ ขอบคุณที่ช่วยนะ
I'm so relieved... Gugu.
โชคดีไปนะ กูกู
What in the world happened?
ตกลงมันเกิดอะไรขึ้น
I don't know. The mansion just started to collapse.
ไม่รู้สิ จู่ๆ บ้านก็เริ่มพังลงมา
Could it be...
ไม่จริงน่า
Gugu!
กูกู
Fushi!
ฟุชิ
Gugu... I'm sorry...
กูกู เป็นความผิดฉันเอง
Because of me... They came...
เพราะฉัน มันถึงได้มา
I knew it.
ว่าแล้วเชียว
Everyone got out...
ทุกคนหนีไปแล้ว
The two of them are the only ones left...
เหลือแค่สองคนนั้น
Get a hold of yourself!
ทำใจดีๆ ไว้
But they've both been hurt.
พวกเขาทั้งคู่บาดเจ็บ
If we don't act fast...
เร็วเข้า ก่อนจะสายเกินไป
Oh, no! It's collapsing!
แย่แล้ว มันจะถล่มลงมาแล้ว
Mom! Dad!
พ่อ แม่
Wait, Gugu! Don't go!
เดี๋ยวก่อน กูกู อย่าเพิ่งไป
I... I love...
ฉัน…เธอ…
Fushi!
ฟุชิ
Where are you?
อยู่ไหน
Fushi! You turned back. It's just like back in the old days.
ฟุชิ อะไรกัน ทำไมตัวเปลี่ยนไปเป็นเหมือนเมื่อก่อนล่ะ
Thanks.
ขอบใจ
Where's the enemy? I'll destroy them!
ศัตรูอยู่ไหน ฉันจะจัดการมัน
I can't see them. They must be hiding.
ยังไม่เห็นเลย มันซ่อนตัวอยู่
There it is! Dodge!
ออกมาแล้ว หนีเร็ว
Looks like it can't stretch its limbs like before.
เจ้านี่สามารถยืดแขนได้เหมือนเมื่อคราวก่อนเหรอ
That'll help us.
ถ้างั้นก็สบายแล้ว
Take this!
ดูนะ
Gugu...
กูกู
This... is not the same.
นี่มัน ไม่เหมือนกับครั้งก่อน
Ah... Fire isn't working.
หา เปลวไฟมอดไปแล้ว
Stone armor?
เกราะหินเหรอ
What the heck is going on?
อะไรกันน่ะ
Gugu, grab on!
กูกู จับนี่ไว้
These creepy things again.
เส้นพวกนั้นอีกแล้ว
Is that monster what's directing them?
หรือว่ามันควบคุมเจ้าพวกนี้อยู่
It's coming for us! It wants to crush us!
แคบลงแล้ว มันจะบีบพวกเราให้ตาย
Fushi! Go ahead!
ฟุชิ ขึ้นไปก่อน
What should we do, Gugu?
กูกู ทำยังไงดี
I... I don't know how to defeat it...
ฉัน…ไม่รู้วิธีที่จะเอาชนะมัน
There's something inside it. Right?
มันมีเนื้อแท้อยู่ข้างในใช่ไหม
Its skin is stone.
ถ้าเป็นอย่างนั้นละก็ ผิวสัมผัสมันก็คือหิน
But it's not clean like a statue.
แต่มันไม่ใช่งานประติมากรรมที่ประณีตสักเท่าไร
Just aggregated stones.
ก็แค่รวบรวมเศษก้อนหินไว้
Inside it is proper meat.
ส่วนข้างในก็เป็นเนื้อธรรมดาๆ
Climb onto it and look for a gap!
ปีนขึ้นไปหาช่องโหว่มันกันเถอะ
Got it!
เข้าใจแล้ว
This stone armor is quite deep!
หินอัดรวมกันเข้าไปเสียลึกเชียว
Fushi, give me a stick!
ฟุชิ ขอไม้หน่อย
I'll pry it open!
ดูนะ ฉันจะงัดมันขึ้นมา
Fushi, that's not enough! Give me more!
ไม่พอ ขอเพิ่มหน่อย
I can see it! Its insides!
เจอแล้ว เนื้อในของมัน
It's soft. It looks like it'll burn well.
ท่าจะนิ่มและติดไฟง่าย
We did it!
ในที่สุด
Destroy that!
ตัดมันเร็ว
Fushi, are you all right?
ฟุชิ เป็นอะไรไหม
I had a chance, but I let it get away.
สบโอกาสแท้ๆ แต่มันกลับหนีไปได้
It just means we're too strong for it.
นั่นหมายความว่าพวกเราแข็งแกร่งยังไงละ
We did it, Fushi!
ทำได้แล้วนะ ฟุชิ
Thanks, Gugu.
กูกู ขอบคุณนะ
If you weren't there, I would have lost again...
ถ้าไม่มีนายละก็คงแพ้ไปแล้ว
I may be immortal, but I'm weak.
เพราะฉันมันอ่อนแอ ทั้งๆ ที่เป็นอมตะแแท้ๆ
If you're ever in trouble, I'll help you.
ถ้านายจะเดือดร้อน ไม่ว่ายังไงฉันก็จะช่วยนาย
That's what brothers are for!
นั่นคือความหมายของพี่น้องยังไงละ
Fu...
ฟุ…
Fu... Fushi!
ฟุ…ฟุชิ
Fushi!
ฟุชิ
Thank goodness. I made it in time!
โชคดีที่มาทัน
Rynn? How long have you been here?
ริง มาตั้งแต่เมื่อไหร่น่ะ
You can't be here...
มาที่นี่ไม่ได้นะ
I have a lot of things to ask you.
ฉันมีเรื่องที่อยากถามนายเยอะมากเลย
But first off, we need to escape.
แต่ก่อนอื่นออกจากที่นี่กันเถอะ
Hurry! This way!
เร็วเข้า ทางนี้
Fushi...
ฟุชิ…
It's crumbling!
มันกำลังถล่ม
Run!
วิ่งเร็ว
What's that cloud of smoke?
ควันนั่นมันอะไรกัน
I'm worried...
รู้สึกใจไม่ดีเลย
Gugu...
กูกู…
This...
นี่มัน…
This isn't my pain...
ไม่ใช่ความเจ็บปวดของฉัน
-What is that? -This isn't good!
-นั่นมันอะไรกัน -แย่แล้วสิ
-Where's our child? -Rynn!
-ลูกล่ะ -ริง
Rynn!
ริง
Are... Are you all right, Rynn?
ปะ…เป็นอะไรไหม ริง
I need to hurry up and...
ถ้าไม่รีบละก็…
It's quite loud outside.
ข้างนอกหนวกหูเนอะ
It... It must be so heavy...
นะ…หนักใช่ไหม
Not at all... It's all right...
เปล่า ไม่ใช่อย่างนั้นหรอก
Don't worry.
วางใจเถอะ
They'll come... and save us...
อีกไม่นานก็คงมีคนมา…ช่วยออกไป
Gugu, don't overexert yourself.
กูกู อย่าฝืนเลย
Flower...
ดอกไม้…
To... Tomorrow... I'll buy you another flower...
พรุ่งนี้…เดี๋ยวจะซื้อมาให้อีก
It'll be all right.
ไม่เป็นไร
No, Gugu.
ไม่ต้องหรอก กูกู
Let's go pick it ourselves.
ไปเก็บด้วยกันเถอะ
I know of only one place where this flower blooms.
ฉันรู้จักที่ที่ดอกไม้นี้บานอยู่แค่ที่เดียวเอง
You know of it too, right, Gugu?
นายก็รู้ใช่ไหม
Of course... We'll definitely go together...
อืม พวกเรา…ไปด้วยกันเถอะ
Rynn...
ริง…
I love you...
ฉันชอบเธอ
No... It can't be!
โกหกน่า เป็นไปไม่ได้
Gugu isn't dead!
กูกูยังไม่ตาย
He isn't dead!
ยังไม่ตาย…
It escaped.
หนีไปแล้ว
It heads to the west.
มันมุ่งหน้าไปทางตะวันตก
You must go after it.
ตามมันไปซะ
Lift this rock!
เอาหินออกเร็ว
Get more people!
ไปเรียกคนมาเพิ่มหน่อย
Yes!
ครับ
Is this all right?
จะดีเหรอ
A part of you lies in that escaped core.
ในแก่นที่หนีไปแล้วนั่นยังมีส่วนหนึ่งของนายอยู่นะ
Oh, you're up.
ตื่นแล้วเหรอ
Brother? What are you doing?
พี่ ทำอะไรอยู่น่ะ
Can't you see? I'm carrying you.
ดูก็รู้แล้วนี่ ฉันแบกนายอยู่ไงละ
Gugu! Welcome back!
กูกู กลับมาแล้วเหรอ
Looks like you've healed up.
ร่างกายไม่เป็นไรแล้วใช่ไหม
All your wounds are gone! You look so nice!
แผลที่บาดเจ็บหายดีหมดแล้ว ดูดีเลยนี่นา
You're right!
จริงด้วย
Wow, Gugu!
กูกู วิเศษไปเลย
Rynn!
ริง
Come on! You made a promise!
งั้นก็รักษาสัญญาที่ให้ไว้กับฉันด้วยละ
Let's go pick flowers together!
ที่ว่าจะไปเก็บดอกไม้ด้วยกันน่ะ
What happened to the enemy?
ศัตรูเป็นยังไงบ้างแล้ว
Did we manage to defeat that huge thing?
เจ้าตัวยักษ์นั่น ล้มไปแล้วเหรอ
What about Fushi? Where is he?
ฟุชิล่ะ หมอนั่นอยู่ไหน
Ah... I see...
อย่างนี้นี่เอง…
Are you really going to leave, Fushi?
ฟุชิ จะไปจริงๆ เหรอ
You don't have to be in such a hurry...
ไม่เห็นต้องรีบขนาดนั้นเลย
The enemy will always come for me.
ศัตรูจะมาในที่ที่ผมอยู่
I can't let anyone else die because of me.
ไม่อยากให้ใครต้องมาตายเพราะผมอีกแล้ว
Shin said he would deal with the aftermath.
ชินบอกว่าจะช่วยเรื่องที่เหลือ
So I don't need to be here any longer.
ดังนั้น ถึงผมจะไม่อยู่ก็ไม่มีปัญหา
Shin, it's time.
คุณชิน ได้เวลาแล้วครับ
Okay.
อืม
You bought so many buns. Where are you taking them?
ซื้อหมั่นโถวมาเยอะขนาดนี้ จะเอาไปไหนเหรอครับ
To my little brother's place.
ไปที่ที่น้องชายอยู่น่ะ
Are all of those for your brother?
หรือว่าทั้งหมดนั่นให้น้องชาย
Yes.
อืม เขาจะกินน่ะ
He's a lot bigger than me.
เพราะเขาตัวใหญ่กว่าฉัน
Gugu!
กูกู
Lady Rynn!
คุณหนูริง
I... had a dream.
ฉันฝันน่ะ
It was the very epitome of happiness.
ฉันฝันเห็นความสุขและอุดมคติ
But something was missing.
แต่มีบางอย่างขาดหายไป
And now I see that. It was my true self.
ฉันพบว่าที่ขาดหายไปนั่น คือตัวตนที่แท้จริงของฉันเอง
Fushi...
ฟุชิ
I have no regrets.
ฉันไม่นึกเสียดายเลย
What's wrong, Fushi?
ฟุชิ มีอะไรเหรอ
What should I do? Looking like this...
ทำยังไงดี ในสภาพอย่างนี้
What should I do?
ทำยังไงดี…
Gugu!
กูกู
You're all right! I'm so glad!
ดีจัง นายปลอดภัยดีสินะ
Gugu... I love you!
กูกู ฉันชอบนาย
Why am I who I am?
ทำไมฉันถึงเป็นฉันกันล่ะ…
Gugu, are you all right?
กูกู เป็นอะไรหรือเปล่า
I'm fine...
ไม่เป็นไร…
Oh, right. What about Fushi? He's around, right?
จริงสิ คุณฟุชิล่ะ เขาก็อยู่ใช่ไหม
Fushi... died.
ฟุชิ...ตายแล้ว
No... It can't be...
โกหกน่า ไม่มีทางเป็นแบบนั้น…
Here... This is his grave.
ดูสิ นี่คือหลุมศพเขา
He was a brave... and wonderful person.
เขาเป็นคนที่…กล้าหาญ และวิเศษมากเลย…
Come, Gugu. Leave the rest to us.
เอาละ กูกู ที่เหลือให้พวกเราจัดการเอง
You need to be going soon, right?
เธอต้องไปแล้วใช่ไหมล่ะ
Ah... yes. That's right.
อืม…ใช่แล้ว
What? Where are you going?
อะไร จะไปไหนเหรอ
Um, well... Shopping.
เอ่อ…ไปซื้อของน่ะ
I... I'll go too. I'll help you.
ฉันก็จะไปช่วยด้วย
Don't worry, Rynn. He'll be fine on his own.
คนเดียวก็พอแล้ว
Another time, Rynn.
ริง ไว้คราวหลังละกันนะ
Then... When you come back...
งั้น…ไว้นายกลับมา
Let's go pick flowers together.
เราไปเก็บดอกไม้ด้วยกันนะ
At the place we promised to.
สถานที่ที่เราสัญญากันไว้
I'll be waiting for you there.
ฉันจะล่วงหน้าไปรอก่อน
Great! I'll be waiting!
ดีจัง ฉันจะรอนายเสมอนะ
Oh, that's right. I have something to return to you.
จริงสิ มีของที่ต้องคืนนายด้วย
Here. Your brother asked me to return it to you.
เอ้านี่ รับฝากมาจากคุณพี่ชายน่ะ
Remember it?
จำได้ใช่ไหม
You should keep it.
ริงเก็บไว้เถอะ
It'll remind you of Gu...
ถ้าทำอย่างนั้นจะได้นึกถึงกู…
Of me.
จะได้นึกถึงฉันยังไงละ
I'm happy! Thanks!
ดีใจจัง ขอบคุณนะ
Here, Gugu. Take these.
กูกู เอานี่ไปซะ
It's not a lot, but here's some food and money.
ถึงจะน้อยแต่ก็มีพวกอาหารกับเงินทอง
Be careful out there.
รักษาตัวด้วยนะ
Thank you...
ขอบคุณครับ
Rynn!
ริง
Rynn! We've been looking all over for you!
ริง หาตั้งนาน
Goodness gracious. As soon as you wake up,
จริงๆ เลย ทันทีที่ลูกตื่น
you come here and stay here until the middle of the night.
ก็มาอยู่ที่แบบนี้จนดึกดื่น
It's bad for your health!
มันไม่ดีต่อสุขภาพนะ
Come on. Let's go back.
เอาละ กลับกันเถอะ
Father, I...
พ่อ หนู…
I won't get married.
หนูจะไม่แต่งงาน
I have someone I love.
หนูมีคนที่ชอบแล้ว
Who?
คนที่ชอบเหรอ ใครล่ะ
I must see him.
รีบให้พ่อเจอเขาเดี๋ยวนี้เลย
Well... He's no longer here.
เขา…ไม่อยู่ที่นี่แล้ว
He's surely... "together" with him.
เขาจะต้องอยู่กับ "เขา" แน่ๆ เลย
In the face of great power,
เมื่ออยู่ต่อหน้าพลังที่ยิ่งใหญ่
a life and memories were taken away.
ชีวิตและความทรงจำที่ถูกช่วงชิงไป
Someone accompanies by an annoyed Fushi's side.
ก็ยังมีคนอยู่เคียงข้างฟุชิที่กำลังเป็นทุกข์
Fushi embarks on a new journey with determination.
พวกฟุชิเริ่มออกเดินทางด้วยใจที่มุ่งมั่น
And new encounters
การพบเจอใหม่ๆ
"EPISODE 13: WILL TOWARD A HIGHER STATE" are coming soon.
"#13 ความมุ่งมั่นที่จะอยู่สูงขึ้น" กำลังรออยู่